A Guide to the International Education Board records FA062
Rockefeller Archive Center
International Education Board records
1910-1964
Rockefeller Archive Center
International Education Board
FA062
36.05 Cubic Feet 93 boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for researchd. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged in four series:
Series 1 - Appropriations
Series 2 - Finances
Series 3 - Minutes, Dockets, Annual Reports
Series 1023 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
The International Education Board was incorporated January 12, 1923, in the state of Virginia. Its purpose was to promote education, institutional or otherwise, throughout the world and as such was a complement to the General Education Board which functioned in the United States. Wickliffe Rose resigned from the International Health Board in 1923 to become director of both boards. At his retirement in 1928, the International Education Board discontinued its active program.
The International Education Board promoted the advancement of education through grants to universities and through a multitude of fellowships to individuals. It sponsored the strengthening of disciplines with such grants as those to develop Mount Palomar and traveling professorships and fellowships. While the main fields of the board were the physical and natural sciences and agriculture, some appropriations were made in the humanities and social sciences as to the American Academy in Rome, the Oriental Institute in Chicago and the New York State Colonization Society for the Booker Washington Agricultural and Industrial Institute of Liberia.
The Board terminated its activities on December 31, 1938.
A history, "Education on an International Scale," was written by George Gray.
The International Education Board records cover the period from 1923 to 1960.
Scope and Contents note
Important subjects in this collection are astronomy, agriculture, rural clubs, physics, chemistry, dairying, biology, marine biology, mathematics, Mount Palomar, Oriental Institute, veterinary medicine, home economics, scientific publications, agricultural education, geology, forestry, Negro education, international education, and the National Research Council.
Among the correspondents are R. A. Millikan, W. W. Bierly, W. S. Richardson, Anson Phelps Stokes, Jackson Davis, W. H. Shepardson, Wickliffe Rose, H. L. Russell, George Foster Peabody, Ray Lyman Wilbur, Frank R. Lillie, Oswald Veblen, Augustus Trowbridge, Abraham Flexner, Simon Flexner, Louise Stanley, H. C. Taylor, Frants P. Lund, Vernon Kellog, W. E. Tisdale, C. B. Hutchison, A. R. Mann, Arthur A. Noyes, A. O. Leuschner, E. G. Nourse, George Asher Hobson, S. T. Dana, Martha van Rensselaer, Florence M. Read, Charles T. Loram, Harlow Shapley, Frank Schlesinger, Charles Breasted, James Breasted, John A. Wilson, Paul Monroe, Thomas H. Morgan, Frank Heath, Albert Einstein, Ernest Rutherford, Nils Bohr, Enrico Fermi, H. von Euler, Marie Curie, and Emil Godlewski.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2B 05
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The records of the International Education Board were deposited with the General Education Board in 1938.
Forests and forestry; African Americans -- Education; Geology; Agricultural education; Astronomy; Veterinary medicine; Home economics; African Americans; International education; Natural history; Education; Dairying; Biology -- Research; Chemistry; Physics; Agriculture; Palomar, Mount (Calif.); Mathematics; Marine biology
- Appropriations, 1920-1960; 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Materials in this series include correspondence, memoranda, charts, clippings, drawings, reports, surveys, manuscripts and reprints.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged into 4 subseries as follows:
  Subseries 1 - Numerical
  Subseries 2 - Foreign Countries
  Subseries 3 - Fellowships in Science
  Subseries 4 - Fellowships in Agriculture
  International Education Board Appropriations Index
  A card index to the International Education Board records, Series 1: Appropriations is available for researcher use. The IEB Appropriations Index provides indexing to Subseries 1.1 through 1.4 in a single series of index cards, arranged A-Z.
  'Subseries 1.1: Numerical' files are indicated by file-numbers ranging from 22 to 4003. For example, file-number "22' indicates the IEB appropriations file "John D. Rockefeller III, 1934-1937" in box 1, folder 1. This collection guide provides file-numbers in the "File Plan Note" for each file.
  'Subseries 1.2: Foreign Countries' files are indicated by a county name, followed by a sequential file number. For example, "Canada 3" indicates the IEB appropriations file "Canada 3 - Ontario Agricultural College, 1923" in box 26, folder 377.
  'Subseries 1.3: Fellowships in Science' files are indicated by the classification "A" in the upper right corner of the index card.
  'Subseries 1.4: Fellowships in Agriculture' files are indicated by the classification "B" in the upper right corner of the index card.
  The IEB Appropriations Index is located in drawers 31-32 of the 72 drawer cabinet next to the RAC's reading room.
  - Numerical, 1
    In addition to information on appropriations, this series also contains administrative folders on staff members and general information on particular organizations in the natural sciences and agriculture.
    As is indicated by the Title, this subseries is arranged numerically. Each file has been assigned an index number, provided in this guide as a File Plan note.
    - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      File Plan note
      22.
    - George J. Beal, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      23.
    - Herman A. Spoehr, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      24.
    - H. J. Thorkelson, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      25.
    - B. M. Duggar, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      26.
    - E. M. East, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Higher education for teachers.
      28.
    - Edward R. Gay, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      29.
    - James R. Agnell, 1925-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      30.
    - Owen D. Young, 1925-1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Finances, international economy, stabilized currency.
      31.
    - Thomas M. Debevoise, 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      32.
    - R. A. Millikan (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Radioactivity and Millikan rays.
      33.
    - Wallace Lund, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      34.
    - Wallace Lund, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - C. E. Beehhofer Roberts, 1924-1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Trip with W. H. Shepardson
      35.
    - W. W. Brierley, 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      36.
    - W. S. Richardson, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Dognin Moths, Survey of health and education in Central America.
      38.
    - Anson Phelps Stokes, 1923-1932 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Encyclopedia of the Negro.
      39.
    - Jackson Davis, 1923-1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      40.
    - Trevor Arnett, 1926-1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Animal breeding.
      41.
    - Paul H. Hanus, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      42.
    - Otis W. Caldwell, 1923-1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Animal breeding, experimental education.
      43.
    - Richard M. Pearce, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      44.
    - George E. Vincent, 1923-1929 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Conservation, McIlhenny club, education in South America.
      45.
    - Max Mason, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      46.
    - Abraham Flexner, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      47.
    - William H. Welch, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      48.
    - E. J. Jaqua, 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Higher education, survey of secondary education in Great Britain.
      49.
    - Translations, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Of farm demonstration work.
      50.
    - Whitney H. Shepardson, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Education surveys, agricultural education, Rhodes scholarships, international relations, fellowships, Country Life Commission.
      51.
    - Whitney H. Shepardson, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Whitney H. Shepardson, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Whitney H. Shepardson, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Whitney H. Shepardson, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Whitney H. Shepardson, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Whitney H. Shepardson - Reports, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wallace Buttrick, 1923-1926 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      52.
    - Raymond B. Fosdick, 1922-1933 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      53.
    - Arthur Woods, 1923-1932 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      54.
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      War relief, trips, invitations, memberships, International Health Board, invitations, General Gorgas.
      55.
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Wickliffe Rose, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Wickliffe Rose - Log, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Wickliffe Rose - Log, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Wickliffe Rose - Fishing, 1923-1928 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Wickliffe Rose - Resignation, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1923-1927 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      56.
    - A. L. Boulware, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      57.
    - Simon Flexner, 1923-1928 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      58.
    - Ralph Hayes, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      Community trust, Sir William Osler.
      59.
    - E. C. Carter, 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      60.
    - Walter Lippman, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      61.
    - John Stewart Bryan, 1923-1937 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      62.
    - Edward Stuart, 1923-1925 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      63.
    - Ruth Savord, 1924-1927 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      64.
    - Charles P. Howland, 1924-1933 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      65.
    - Augustus Trowbridge, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      66.
    - Ernest A. Buttrick, 1925-1931 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      67.
    - National Manufacturers Company, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      69.
    - International House, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      Harry Edmonds, Frederick Osborne.
      70.
    - International House, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - International House, 1923-1926 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - International House, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - International House - Pamphlets (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Frank R. Lillie, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      Biology laboratory survey.
      74.
    - International Education Board, 1922-1947 (Box 5, Folder 72)
      Virginia charter, methods of operation, organization, authority to operate in New York, incorporation, finances, leases, securities, tax exemption, dissolution.
      100.
    - International Education Board, 1922-1947 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - International Education Board, 1922-1947 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - International Education Board, 1922-1947 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - International Education Board, 1922-1947 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - International Education Board - Certificate of Incorporation (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - International Education Board - Documents of Record (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - International Education Board - Reports (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - International Education Board - Liberalization of Past Gifts, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 80)
      100.1
    - International Education Board - Treasurer, 1923-1938 (Box 5, Folder 81)
      102.
    - International Education Board - Minutes, 1923-1932 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      103.
    - International Education Board - Officers and Members, 1925-1936 (Box 5, Folder 83)
      104.
    - International Education Board - Proxies, 1923-1937 (Box 5, Folder 84)
      106.
    - International Education Board - History, 1923-1941 (Box 6, Folder 85)
      107.
    - International Education Board - History, 1923-1941 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - International Education Board - History, Printing, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - International Education Board - Bylaws (Box 6, Folder 88)
      109.
    - International Education Board - Certificate of Incorporation (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Appropriations, 1923-1938 (Box 6, Folder 90)
      113.
    - Appropriations, 1923-1938 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Appropriations, 1923-1938 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Gifts and Pledges, 1923-1937 (Box 6, Folder 93)
      114.
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 1925-1927 (Box 6, Folder 94)
      115.
    - Nomination Committee, 1925-1927 (Box 6, Folder 95)
      117.
    - Finance Committee, 1924-1939 (Box 6, Folder 96)
      118.
    - European Office, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      French income tax, European economy, accounts and financial procedure, administration.
      120.
    - European Office, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - European Office, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - European Office, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - European Office, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - European Office - Audit, 1927-1928 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - European Office - Financial Procedure, 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - European Office - Financial Reports, 1925-1934 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - European Office - Financial Reports, 1925-1934 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - European Office - Income Tax, 1926-1930 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - European Office - Income Tax, 1926-1930 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Rockefeller Institute, 1925-1926 (Box 7, Folder 108)
      121.
    - International Educational Board - Possibilities, 1924-1927 (Box 7, Folder 109)
      131.2
    - Mathematicians, 1923-1927 (Box 8, Folder 110)
      134.
    - Committee on International Co-operation, 1924-1928 (Box 8, Folder 111)
      Of the League of Nations.
      136.
    - International Health Board, 1923-1926 (Box 8, Folder 112)
      Death of St. Darling.
      150.
    - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1923-1928 (Box 8, Folder 113)
      151.
    - Chase National Bank, 1923-1937 (Box 8, Folder 114)
      Also Equitable Trust Company; securities.
      152.
    - Forms (Box 8, Folder 115)
      153.
    - National Educational Association, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 116)
      Journal
      154.
    - Chase Safe Deposit Company, 1925-1932 (Box 8, Folder 117)
      Also Equitable Safe Deposit Company.
      155.
    - International Health Board - Salvador, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 118)
      Education reports.
      201.
    - United States Department of Agriculture, 1923-1926 (Box 8, Folder 119)
      Home economics, demonstration agents, rural extension work. Louise Stanley, H. C. Taylor, Frants P. Lund, O. B. Marlen.
      202.
    - Interoffice Memoranda, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 120)
      203.
    - Interboard Luncheons, 1924-1927 (Box 8, Folder 121)
      Mussolini, university presses, India medical education, industrial relations, Nicaraguan politics, Central America, China, Negro education, medical education, smallpox, yellow fever, mental hygiene, Russia, Africa.
      203.1
    - Central Committee, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 122)
      Like Advisory Committee.
      203.3
    - Pan American Union, 1923-1929 (Box 8, Folder 123)
      Fellowships, studies, congresses, education.
      204.
    - South Carolina Co-operative Extension Work, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 124)
      Preservation of rural life.
      205.
    - National Research Council, 1923-1929 (Box 8, Folder 125)
      Fellowships, international education, education of women. Vernon Kellog, Oswald Veblen.
      206.
    - International Critical Tables, 1924-1928 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      National Research Council project to publish data in physics, chemistry and technology.
      206a
    - International Research Council, 1925-1928 (Box 9, Folder 127)
      206b
    - National Research Council Fellowships, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 128)
      Administration of International Education Board fellows, co-operation between boards.
      206c
    - National Research Council Fellowships, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - National Research Council Fellowships, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - National Research Council Fellowships, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - National Research Council Fellowships, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - National Research Council Fellowships, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - Institute of International Education, 1923-1929 (Box 9, Folder 134)
      207.
    - Legations, 1923-1925 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      208.
    - National Catholic Welfare Council, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 136)
      209.
    - World Conference on Education, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 137)
      210.
    - North Carolina - Agriculture, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 138)
      211.
    - Worlds Dairy Congress Association, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 139)
      212.
    - Worlds Agriculture Society, 1923-1924 (Box 9, Folder 140)
      Congress, relationships to International Institute of Agriculture, journal.
      213.
    - United States Scientists, 1923-1928 (Box 10, Folder 141)
      Lists, fields.
      214.
    - United States Scientists, 1923-1928 (Box 10, Folder 142)
    - Scientific Center Maps, 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 143)
    - Foreign Scientists, 1923-1927 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      214a
    - Foreign Scientists, 1923-1927 (Box 10, Folder 145)
    - Foreign Scientists, 1923-1927 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    - Scientific Centers, 1927-1928 (Box 10, Folder 147)
      214b
    - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1923-1924 (Box 10, Folder 148)
      215.
    - Federal Board for Vocational Education, 1923-1925 (Box 10, Folder 149)
      Agriculture. C. H. Lane.
      217.
    - Society for Visual Education, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 150)
      Motion Pictures.
      218.
    - Pan Pacific Union, 1923-1926 (Box 11, Folder 151)
      Research studies, institute. To promote friendly relations among nations bordering to Pacific. A. H. Ford, Frank Bunker.
      219.
    - Pan Pacific Union, 1923-1926 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - Pan Pacific Union - Reports (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - Philadelphia Interstate Diary Council, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 154)
      220.
    - Educational Commission to East Africa, 1923-1927 (Box 11, Folder 155)
      Of the Phelps Stokes Fund.
      221.
    - Charles T. Loram, 1924-1926 (Box 11, Folder 156)
      Fellowships, African political situation, Jeanes Teachers, segregation, Educational Commission.
    - African Educators, 1924-1926 (Box 11, Folder 157)
      221.1
    - Surveys, 1924-1926 (Box 11, Folder 158)
      Near and Far East, influence of American education or agricultural education, social studies in Europe, rural social conditions in Europe.
      222.
    - Astronomical Union, 1926-1929 (Box 11, Folder 159)
      Surveys of minor planets, bibliography of planetary research. A. O. Leuschner, Vernon Kellog.
      222.1
    - Forestry - Fellowships, 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 160)
      223.
    - Agriculture - Legal Studies, 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 161)
      H. C. Taylor, E. G. Nourse.
      224.
    - Bibliographies, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 162)
      225.
    - Traveling Professorships, 1924-March 1928 (Box 11, Folder 163)
      226.
    - Traveling Professorships, 1924-March 1928 (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - Traveling Professorships, 1924-March 1928 (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - Traveling Professorships, 1924-March 1928 (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - Traveling Professorships, April 1928-1929 (Box 12, Folder 167)
    - Traveling Professorships - Heady, Hardy and Threlfall, 1924-1925 (Box 12, Folder 168)
      Fisheries, industrial research, engineering.
    - Traveling Professorships - Otto Appel, 1926-1933 (Box 12, Folder 169)
      Plant pathology.
    - Traveling Professorships - Ernest Babcock, 1924-1926 (Box 12, Folder 170)
      Genetics.
    - Traveling Professorships - George Berkhoff, 1925-1927 (Box 12, Folder 171)
      Mathematical physics.
    - Traveling Professorships - John Black, 1926-1928 (Box 12, Folder 172)
      Agricultural economics.
    - Traveling Professorships - Gary Calkins, 1926-1927 (Box 12, Folder 173)
      Zoology.
    - Traveling Professorships - Royal Chapman, 1926-1927 (Box 12, Folder 174)
      Entomology.
    - Traveling Professorships - Alexander Ciuca, 1925-1930 (Box 12, Folder 175)
      Pathology.
    - Traveling Professorships - R. E. Clausen, 1926-1928 (Box 12, Folder 176)
      Genetics and herbaria.
    - Traveling Professorships - L. C. Dunn, 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 177)
      Animal genetics.
    - Traveling Professorships - H. M. Evans, 1927-1929 (Box 12, Folder 178)
      Animal nutrition and physiology.
    - Traveling Professorships - E. Faure-Fremiet, 1926-1930 (Box 12, Folder 179)
      Biology.
    - Traveling Professorships - Karl Friedericks, 1927-1929 (Box 12, Folder 180)
    - Traveling Professorships - Frederiksen and Svendsen-Tune, Svensson, 1927-1929 (Box 12, Folder 181)
      Agricultural club work.
    - Traveling Professorships - Boris Gerasimovic, 1926-1928 (Box 12, Folder 182)
      Astronomy.
    - Traveling Professorships - E. Godlewski, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 183)
    - Traveling Professorships - Ejnar Hertzsprung, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 184)
    - Traveling Professorships - Hendrik Hesselman, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 185)
      Forestry.
    - Traveling Professorships - Ivan C. Jagger, 1924-1927 (Box 13, Folder 186)
    - Traveling Professorships - Lauder Jones, 1925-1927 (Box 13, Folder 187)
      Chemistry.
    - Traveling Professorships - E. J. Kraus, 1926-1928 (Box 13, Folder 188)
      Botany.
    - Traveling Professorships - T. S. Kuo, 1926-1927 (Box 13, Folder 189)
      Plant breeding and agricultural administration.
    - Traveling Professorships - O. H. Larsen, 1924-1931 (Box 13, Folder 190)
      Agriculture.
    - Traveling Professorships - Hendrik Lundegardh, 1925-1927 (Box 13, Folder 191)
      Plant physiology.
    - Traveling Professorships - W. J. McKee, 1925-1927 (Box 13, Folder 192)
      Rural education.
    - Traveling Professorships - C. Mendenhall, 1925-1927 (Box 13, Folder 193)
      Physics and chemistry.
    - Traveling Professorships - Stanislaus Minkiewicz, 1926-1936 (Box 13, Folder 194)
      Economic entomology.
    - Traveling Professorships - Jan Molloff, 1926-1927 (Box 13, Folder 195)
    - Traveling Professorships - William I. Myers, 1926-1927 (Box 13, Folder 196)
      Agricultural economics and farm equipment.
    - Traveling Professorships - Austin Patterson, 1924-1926 (Box 13, Folder 197)
    - Traveling Professorships - Otto Rahn, 1925-1926 (Box 13, Folder 198)
      Dairy physics.
    - Traveling Professorships - C. L. Roadhouse, 1926-1928 (Box 13, Folder 199)
      Dairying.
    - Traveling Professorships - Ivan Tragardh, 1926-1928 (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Traveling Professorships - R. A. Wardle, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 201)
      Economic ecology.
    - Traveling Professorships - Fredrick Weber, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 202)
      Biology and agriculture.
    - Maps - Europe (Box 14, Folder 203)
      227.
    - Manne Siegbahn, 1924-1925 (Box 14, Folder 204)
      Physics.
      230.
    - Othenio Abel, 1924-1928 (Box 14, Folder 205)
      Paleobiology.
      231.
    - Marie Curie, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 206)
      232.
    - Association of Land Grant Colleges, 1923-1926 (Box 14, Folder 207)
      234.
    - United States Department of State, 1924-1925 (Box 14, Folder 208)
      235.
    - Forestry, 1924-1927 (Box 14, Folder 209)